<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tools on MLIR</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Tools/</link><description>Recent content in Tools on MLIR</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 15:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MLIR : Language Server Protocol</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Tools/MLIRLSP/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Tools/MLIRLSP/</guid><description>MLIR LSP Language Server : mlir-lsp-server Supporting custom dialects Features PDLL LSP Language Server : mlir-pdll-lsp-server Compilation Database Features TableGen LSP Language Server : tblgen-lsp-server Compilation Database Features Language Server Design Communication and Transport Language Server Protocol Language-Specific Server Editor Plugins Visual Studio Code This document describes the tools and utilities related to supporting LSP IDE language extensions for various MLIR-related languages. An LSP language extension is generally comprised of two components; a language client and a language server.</description></item><item><title>MLIR Reduce</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Tools/mlir-reduce/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Tools/mlir-reduce/</guid><description>How to Use it Write the script for testing interestingness Available reduction strategies Operation elimination Rewrite patterns into simpler forms Reduce with built-in optimization passes Build a custom mlir-reduce Future works An MLIR input may trigger bugs after series of transformations. To root cause the problem or help verification after fixes, developers want to be able to reduce the size of a reproducer for a bug. This document describes mlir-reduce, which is similar to bugpoint, a tool that can reduce the size of the input needed to trigger the error.</description></item></channel></rss>